LUCA IACONELLI

EXPERIENCES

Luca laconelli

Freelance/Contract | Jul 2020 - now

Developer of high-performance, responsive applications for web, mobile, and native platforms: UI/UX implementation (layout, styling, accessibility), performance engineering (optimization, caching, offline access), quality assurance (testing, CI/CD integration)

Illimity Bank

Full stack developer | Jul 2019 - Aug 2020

Led the Frontend team, ensuring high-quality code delivery within deadlines, selected technologies and architectural designs aligned with company requirements, focusing on code quality and consistency. This role allowed me to stay up-to-date with frontend best practices and continually improve my development, communication, and mentorship skills

IT Auction

Full stack developer | Apr 2017 - Jul 2019

Developed a data-driven, serverless corporate web application using cutting-edge technologies. This experience allowed me to refine my skills in SSR and data-driven application development, further expanding my proficiency in Frontend technologies

Studio Mado

Full stack developer | Dec 2015 - Apr 2017

Developed and maintained high-end front-end applications, utilizing a range of technologies including JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, CSS3/Sass, and HTML5

IDEARTE Design

Co-Founder/Lead developer | Dec 2015 - Jul 2019

My digital agency specialized in growth-driven web solutions

SED Web Agency

Full stack developer | Dec 2014 - Dec 2015

Design and development of many e-commerce, e-learning platforms, landing pages and custom plugins on the WordPress platform plus the development of mobile applications

Beta Formazione

FrontEnd developer | Dec 2013 - Dec 2014

Design and development of many e-commerce and e-learning platforms

Your3Minutes

Full stack developer | Mar 2014 - Aug 2014

Multilingual web video-recruitment platform, which can also be used on mobile phones

Studio Abacus

Programming Tutor & Mentor | May 2011 - Aug 2014

Mentored students from multiple schools, adapting explanations to individual learning styles

GEMOS

Full stack developer | Jul 2009 - Dec 2013

Provided comprehensive technical support for 700+ employees across 200+ systems

EDUCATION

Google online-Degree sponsored by a Google-scholarship

Google Mobile and Web Specialist | October 2017 - Sept 2018

Institute of IT, Math and Statistics

Information Technology Abacus | Sept 2005 - Jul 2009

Philosophy, Photography, Microsoft Office, Computer security

Extra |

SKILLS

[{ "name": " Problem solving" }, { "name": " Full stack" }, { "name": " Creative" }]

- AWS
- S3
- NuxtJs
- VueJs
- WordPress
- jQuery
- CSS
- ReactJs
- MySQL
- W3C

- Azure
- NodeJs
- Git
- Accessibility
- Unit test
- E2E
- Jest
- Docker
- Cordova
- Webpack

- i18n
- ThreeJs
- TypeScript
- Agile
- Angular
- Nativescript
- RestAPI
- Electron
- C#
- Figma

About me

With 15+ years in frontend development, I specialize in building high-performance applications using VueJs and NuxtJs.

Strong>As an official NuxtJs contributor and VueJs conference speaker, I combine technical expertise with a passion for open-source and mentoring;

Strong>Available for remote contract work worldwide;

Strong>Graduated and